Shri Ganesha Puja
“Chastity and Collective Nature”
锡吕格涅沙崇拜
贞洁和集体性
Cabella Ligure, Italy
September 5, 1998
意大利坎贝拉 1998年9月5日
Today we are going to worship Shri Ganesh.
I think I have told you a lot about Him and
今天我们会崇拜锡吕格涅沙 我想我已经告诉过你们许多有关祂和
His nature, but still so many of us have not
yet realized what are His powers, and what
祂的本质的情况 但我们当中还有许多人没有认识到什么是祂的力量 什么是
He wants.
祂的需要
First and foremost thing is that to respect
Shri Ganesha is to understand the importance
首先 最重要的是 尊重锡吕格涅沙就是要明白贞洁的重要性
of chastity. Chastity is not only for the
women, it is more for the men to observe.
贞洁并不只是针对女性 男性更要遵守
If you have self-respect, in the real sense
of the word, you will take to chastity without
如果你有自尊 真正意义上的自尊 你将会毫无困难地接纳贞洁
any difficulties. But if you have no self-respect,
then you run after something which is very
但是如果你没有自尊 那么你就会追逐一些非常低级的
low, of a very degrading quality. So it’s
very important that chastity must be respected,
可耻的事物 因此 贞洁必须被尊重
must be understood, and must be imbibed. This
habit of not observing the proper protocol
必须被明了 必须被接受 这是非常重要的 这种不遵守正确的贞洁礼仪的习惯
of the chastity develops from childhood, and
we’ll have to be very careful, when we are
自幼年时期就发展起来 我们不得不非常小心 当我们
in a Ganesha state we should not take to such
horrible things.
处在格涅沙的状态 我们不该接受这些恐怖的事
I don’t know from where people get the ideas.
As you see today in the whole world there’s
我不知道人们是从哪里得来这些想法的 如你所看到的 在整个世界
a crisis of chastity. In the West specially,
we have heard of so many cases of child abuse.
存在贞洁的危机 尤其在西方 我们听到过如此多的虐待儿童的事件
In a temple of God one should not even take
the name of this dirty disease which has grabbed
在神的殿中 一个人甚至不该提起这种攫取人心的肮脏疾病的名字来
the people. But in India we have never heard
of it, we don’t know. Of course, some of
但在印度 我们从没有听说过它 我们不知道 当然
the men are very, very ruined people and they
can’t help it, unless and until they are
有些人是非常非常富毁灭性的 他们无法自拨
put into jail.
直到被送进监狱
But for a Sahaja yogi it is very important
to look after our chastity. As I told you
但是对于霎哈嘉瑜伽修习者来说 照看好我们的贞洁是非常重要的 正如我昨天告诉你们的
yesterday, it is not necessary to find a girl
for yourself or a boy for yourself. It’s
没有必要为自己找个女孩或男孩
also against the rules of chastity. I’m
not saying that you should allow only your
那也是违反贞洁规则的 我不是说你们只能让你们的父母
parents to decide, but let the Sahaja Yoga
decide, because you are Sahajis. You are born
做决定 而是让霎哈嘉瑜伽来决定 因为你们是霎哈嘉瑜伽练习者
after the image of Ganesha, who ultimately
becomes Christ. So what should be your attitude
你们出生的形象来自格涅沙 祂最终成为基督 因此你们以什么态度
towards chastity is very important. The most
important thing, that if we get ruined on
对待贞洁是非常重要的 最重要的事情是 如果我们的贞洁层面
our chastity level then Sahaja Yoga is very,
very difficult, and it doesn’t give you
遭到破坏 那么霎哈嘉瑜伽（自然而然的瑜伽）将非常非常困难 她也不会给你
that blessing as you should have.
你本该享有的祝福
You saw yesterday people from Romania and
also from Ukraine were singing so beautifully.
昨天 你们看到罗马尼亚人 还有乌克兰人 歌唱得如此漂亮
One of the reasons is that basically they
are very, very humble people. They’re humbled
其中一个原因是 基本上他们都非常非常谦卑 他们如此的谦卑
down, so much so that they have given up nonsensical
ideas about sex life and all that. So the
以致他们放弃了有关性生活等等所有那些的荒唐念头 所以
humility will teach you that you are not having
your self-respect.
这谦卑将教会你 （当贞洁遭到破坏时）你并没有自尊
In the Islam they’ve stressed a very big
importance on chastity, very much so. And
伊斯兰教里 人们对贞洁赋予了非常大的重视 重视非常大
this was gone to such an extent that Mohammed
Sahib said that you can have five wives or
这重视如此之深 以致先知默罕默德说 你们可以有五个妻子
four wives, but you don’t have women who
are prostitutes. Once this chastity starts
或四个妻子 但你们不要娶妓女 一旦贞洁离我们而去
leaving us, we don’t mind anything under
the sun. We have seen results of that working
我们不会在乎天下任何事 在许多非常高位的人身上
out in many people who are very highly placed.
And these highly placed people think that
我们已经见过这样的结果 这些非常高位的人自以为
they are something great, and they can overcome
the binding of Jesus Christ and they can do
他们是非常伟大的 以为他们可以挣脱耶稣基督的束缚 以为他们可以
what they like, go on misbehaving with women
who are under them. They may do it secretly,
为所欲为 不断地与他们手下的妇女行为不端 他们也许私下里如此
they may do it any way, but Ganesha watches
that, and He punishes them for what they are
也许是任何其它的方式 但格涅沙都看着 并因他们的所为惩罚他们
doing. It’s a terrible thing to go into
these kind of ventures, which are not the
冒这种险是可怕的 霎哈嘉瑜伽士不会涉足
field of Sahaja yogis. Sahaja yogis have to
first of all steady their eyes, because it
霎哈嘉瑜伽士要首先稳定他们的眼睛 因为这
is concerned with the power of Jesus Christ.
But in all the Christian nations I have seen
关系到耶稣基督的力量 但在所有基督教国家
people have wandering eyes – very surprising,
when Christ is their leader, they worship
我看到人们眼神游移 非常奇怪 既然基督是他们的领袖
Christ, go to church, sing the praise of Christ,
and they have wandering eyes all over. These
他们崇拜基督 去到教堂 唱基督的赞歌
然而却到处是眼神游移的人们 这些
wandering eyes cannot be representative of
the chastity of Christ.
游移的眼神绝不可能是基督贞洁的代表
Now the second point is that the power of
Ganesha can only be manifested if you are
其次 格涅沙的力量只能在你明智时得以彰显
wise, because He’s the giver of wisdom.
Now people don’t understand what is wisdom
因为祂是智慧的给予者
现如今 人们不明白什么是智慧
is – this is a big problem. Intelligence,
so-called, is not wisdom. It can make you
这是个大难题 所谓的智力上聪明 并不是智慧 聪明可使你
a very cunning, very aggressive, and sometimes
very subtle person who can go on deceiving
成为一个非常狡猾 非常好斗 有时非常阴险的人 这种人可以经常骗人
people, telling lies, doing all kinds of things,
and believing in themselves that they are
说谎 做尽所有（这些）事 还相信自己是非常
very, very successful. Success is never the
criteria of a Sahaja yogi. Success in Sahaja
非常成功 （这种）成功绝不是一个霎哈嘉瑜伽士的标准 霎哈嘉瑜伽中的
Yoga means very subtle surrendering of oneself
to Sahaja Yoga. That is seldom to be found
成功意味着非常精微的向霎哈嘉瑜伽交托自己 这种成功很少实现
unless and until you meditate every day. It’s
very important that you must meditate. Those
除非而且只当你们每天静坐冥想 每天冥想非常重要 那些
who do not meditate will be lost to Sahaja
Yoga, because wisdom can only grow through
不冥想的人会失去霎哈嘉瑜伽 因为智慧只能借由你的内在启迪
your inner inspiration. You can have this
inner inspiration only if the power of Shri
得到成长 仅当格涅沙的力量彰显 你才可以拥有这内在启迪
Ganesha manifests. He is the giver of your
wisdom. In the wisdom what you do is to find
祂是你智慧的给予者 在这智慧中 你要做的是去找到解决方案
solutions, solutions which are peaceful, which
are satisfying, which are soothing.
那和平 满足 抚慰人心的解决方案
He is the one who takes you to task also.
Like yesterday I was told there was a whirlwind,
祂也是给你麻烦的那位 像昨天 我被告知来了旋风
and many people had to suffer a little bit
because of the wind that came and blew off
许多人不得不受点苦楚 因为旋风到来 吹掉了
your tents. There’s no need to have tents
in this climate, what is the need? I don’t
你们的帐篷 在这样的气候里搭帐篷 无此需要 有什么需要呢
understand. But they cannot live without a
tent, you see. I can sleep outside very nicely,
我不明白 但他们没有帐篷就无法住下 你看 我可以很好地睡在外面
on the street also. So there’s no need to
sort of fuss about all these things and bring
也可以睡在大街上 所以无需小题大做 为这些事情烦恼
the whole household here, there’s no need.
We should not be afraid of discomfort. If
要把整个家搬来 无此需要
我们不该害怕不舒适 如果
you want to have a very comfortable life and
you can’t suffer any discomfort, you are
你想舒适过活 那你便不能忍受任何不适 你对霎哈嘉瑜伽
no good for Sahaja Yoga. In olden days people
used to go to Himalayas, stand on one leg
没有好处 古时侯 人们经常去到喜马拉雅山 单脚站立
and pray to God, and they didn’t give realization,
they couldn’t get realization; while you
向神祷告 他们没有（被）给予自觉
他们得不到自觉 然而你们
all have got realization. So one should not
try to make oneself very, very sort of a lordly
都得到自觉 所以一个人不该试着让自己变成非常非常 某种 贵族气派
person. There is no need to care for comfort.
I can live in comfort and I can live in any
的人 无需在意舒适 我可以在舒适中生活 我也可以在任何方式下生活
way, at this age also.
以现在的年纪
So what you have to do is to, not to practice,
I say, asceticism but to become an ascetic.
因此你要做的是 不是去练习 我要说 禁欲主义 而是成为一个清心寡欲的人
Practicing means trouble, but if you just
become an ascetic from within, then you don’t
练习意味着麻烦 但要是你从内里成为清心寡欲的人 那么你不会
bother about these little, little things here
and there. But our style is still molded by
为这里那里的这些小小的事情起烦恼 但是我们的风格依然
outside world. We haven’t got our own world,
then we are going as the fashion is; and once
受造于外在的世界 我们还没有我们自己的世界 我们随着时尚在走 一旦
you start going with the fashion, the wisdom
disappears. I never tell anybody that you
你们开始跟随时尚 智慧消失了 我决不是说你们
don’t have this fashion or that fashion
or anything. It’s your wisdom which will
不要这种时尚或那种时尚或任何其它的 是你的智慧
teach you. Wisdom will teach you how to regulate
yourself, because you have come here to ascend,
要教导你 智慧将教导你如何调整自己 因为你们来到这里 为要升进
to achieve a very special place in the realm
of spirituality.
要在灵性的王国中 达至一个非常特殊的位置
I must stress again on the power of wisdom.
Before doing anything you should just appeal
我必须要再次强调智慧的力量，在你做任何事情之前
to your wisdom and find out if it is wise
to be like that. With this practice you will
都需要参考你的智慧找出这样做是否是明智的 由这个练习，你将会
reduce your temper, absolutely. You’ll reduce
your lust, you’ll reduce your guilt very
减少你的脾气，毫无疑问。你将会减少贪婪以及罪疚
much; because once you start understanding
that there’s no wisdom in feeling guilty,
因为一旦你开始意识到感到内疚是毫无智慧的
your guilt will disappear.
你的罪疚将会消失
Also the worst thing is that we have a great
desire to have this, have that, and to indulge
同样糟糕的是我们有非常多的欲望，想要这个，想要那个
into all kinds of greed. This greed becomes
zero as soon as you understand wisely that
沉浸在各种各样的贪念之中，一旦你能够理智的懂得完全没有贪心的必要时，
there’s no need. Otherwise all the time
you’ll be thinking about yourself, about
你的贪婪将会消失。否则你会无时无刻想着自己，想着你的健康
your health, about your children, about your
house, whatever is supposed to be yours. But
你的孩子，你的房子，或是你拥有的其他什么
the death proves that there’s nothing belongs
to you. You have come alone, and you have
但是，死亡证明了没有任何一个事物是属于你的，你是独自来到这个世间
to go alone. This is the wisdom which is to
be imbibed. You cannot practice it, you cannot
而且你必须要独自离开。这是需要理解的智慧。你无法练习它
force it, but it’s to be imbibed through
your spirituality.
无法强迫它，但可以通过灵性而被吸收它
Then the greatest thing that happens is the
joy, joy of the dancing of Shri Ganesh. Like
接着发生最美好的事情是喜悦，锡吕 格涅沙舞蹈的喜悦
a child you see Him dancing; how joyous He
feels, and you also feel. In the same way,
像是一个小孩你看到他跳舞，他是多么喜悦，你也同样能感受到。同样地，
a little child being born within you, and
you start behaving like a small child. Normally
一个小孩在你的内里出生，而你也开始变得像个小孩子，
it has no sense of lust, greed, nothing. It
knows how to share. So this is the position,
通常，小孩子没有贪婪的感觉，没有。他知道如何去分享，因此，在这个位置上
we say, that you become a gana – the army
of Shri Ganesh, they are ganas and they’re
我们说，你变成了gana，锡吕 格涅沙的军队的一员，他们是
very powerful. And they do all the work of
the world, they live in this world, but all
非常有力量的。并且他们成就世界上的所有事情，他们活在这个世界上，
their source of energy is from the Divine.
但是他们的能量来源于上天
So Shri Ganesha is an Omkara. He’s the first
created deity by the Goddess, because He’s
因此，锡吕格涅沙是一个Omkara，他是女神最先创造的神祇，
auspiciousness. So first auspiciousness is
created for our good. We are auspicious because
因为他是吉祥的，因此首先吉祥是为了我们的好处而创造的。我们因为锡吕格涅沙而吉祥。
of Shri Ganesha. Some people, if they are
in the house they create problems. They are
有些人，如果他们在房间内，他们会制造问题。
always creating problems out of nothing. They
are not auspicious people. Those who are peacemakers,
他们总会莫名制造问题。他们是不吉祥的。但那些和平的制造者，
those who are loving are the ones who are
blessed by Shri Ganesha. What is the wisdom
那些爱其他人的人是受到锡吕格涅沙的祝福的。争斗有任何的智慧可言么？
in fighting? You should find out, what is
the wisdom in fighting? Why are you fighting,
你应当找出，为什么你们要争斗
for what things? For small, small things,
things that you can yourself correct? Why
为了什么？为了那些非常非常小的事情，而这些你们自己就可以纠正，
should you fight? If you have a fighting nature,
that means Ganesha is against you, is your
为什么要争斗呢？如果你天性如此，那意味着锡吕 格涅沙是与你相反的，
Ganesha is sleeping; that power is not with
you, there is no wisdom in it. In this world,
你内在的锡吕格涅沙是沉睡的，它的力量不在。那里没有智慧。
all those great people who have been respected
since centuries have been very, very wise
从古至今，世上那些被人尊敬的伟大的人都是非常非常明智的。
people – not hot-tempered, not people who
were quarreling, not people who were having
那些坏脾气的，总是争吵的，贪婪的，为了他们所谓的生命目标的人
lust as the aim of their life. Such people
will be never remembered by the progeny.
这样的人永不会被后人记住。
But that’s not so important, as you as Sahaja
yogis are very important. You are here on
那些都不重要，重要的是你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。你来到这个世界上
this earth to emancipate the whole of humanity.
So, what should be the aim of your life is
是为了参与到全人类的解放。所以，你生命的目标应当是
to go deep into your spirituality. This aim
of getting into spirituality, I think you
深入你的灵性，这才是你的目标。
all know, you see, but you do not work out.
I have told you last time that your attention
你们都知道，但是你们却不能成就，我上次已经告诉过你们，你们的注意力应当是内在的，
has to be inside, not outside, and you should
not react. All these procedures help you to
而不是外在的。你不需要起反应。所有这些过程都会帮助你变得明智。
be wise, to be sensible. But the sensible
person who is just sensible as far as his
但是那些明智的人只会在对自己舒适得事物上明智，例如，他们的金钱，
own comforts are concerned, money is concerned
or his own health is concerned – everything
他们的健康，所有这些事物上的明智不是真正的明智。
encompassing him – is not a wise person.
He’s not wise. If you see a little child,
假如你看到一个小孩，如果他受到很好的教养，当然，他会一直关心其他人，
who is properly brought up of course, he will
always bother about other people. He’ll
他会找出其他人需要什么
find out what others need, what are, what
can make them happy. He’ll listen all the
什么事情会使得他们开心。他会倾听所有那些简单的方法，
simple methods, he will try to please others,
but not to gain any favor or to show off that
他会尝试取悦其他人，但不是为了获得什么好处或是炫耀他是慷慨的，
he’s very generous, but in the real sense
of the word, that gives him joy. That is the
但是在真正意义上，这些付出给他喜悦的感觉，
Collectivity.
这就是集体。
Today I am going to tell you something more
about this collective nature that comes to
今天我将会讲述多一些集体的特质，它来源于你内在的锡吕格涅沙的努力
you through Shri Ganesha’s efforts, or we
can say His powers. Somebody told Me that
或者我们可以说是他的力量，有些人告诉我
Einstein has already made a story like that,
is a discovery that if you all become cool,
爱因斯坦已经提出一个故事，像是一个发现：你们是否都能在锡吕格涅沙的祝福下
that is under the Shri Ganesha’s blessing,
then we all become one. That’s his theory.
变得清凉，同时所有人成为一体。这是他的理论。
But we also had Phil Ward here who established
that when you cool down the helium gas, all
但是我们同样也有Phil Ward ,他提出，当你冷却氦气时，
the molecules or you can call them atoms,
they start moving in a collective way. Otherwise
所有的分子或是你们称为的原子，它们开始以一种集体的方式运动。否则，
they are hitting each other, they are beating
each other and they are running helter and
它们会相互撞击，互相冲撞。
skelter. In the same way, when we have Shri
Ganesha’s blessing within us in the real
同样地，当我们拥有锡吕格涅沙的祝福时，
sense of the word, with our wisdom, then what
happens, we become very much evolved Sahaja
我们开始变成进化了的霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
yogis. “Evolved Sahaja yogis” are, means
they have become one. “One” means what?
“进化了的霎哈嘉瑜伽士”的意思是你们都成为一体。这个“一体”又是指的什么呢？
“One” means they all live for each other,
they enjoy each other, they see the comfort
“一体”意味着你们相互为彼此而活，享受彼此，
of each other.
看到彼此的需求。
For example, the people who are very rich,
people who are very poor, people who are sick,
例如，有些人非常富有，有些人很贫穷，有些人是生病的
people who are healthy, all of them combined
together as one: in Sanskrit it is called
有些人很健康，所有这些人都被吸纳成为一个整体，在梵文中被称为
“eka karita” – they become one. And
this oneness shows in your celebrations, when
“eka karita”-他们成为一个整体。而这个一体性会在你们的庆祝中显现。
you all come here you try to help each other
all the time, I have seen. Nobody minds helping
当你们所有人都相互帮助时，我曾经看到，没有人会介意
each other. I have seen people enjoying each
other. They do not want to hurt anyone; on
帮助他人。我看到人们享受帮助他人。他们不想让其他人受伤。
the contrary, they want to be helpful and
sensible with each other. Most of your leaders
相反的，他们想要变得对彼此更有有帮助并且是明智的。
I have chosen who are very wise, who avoid
problems, who do not get into panics, most
我选择的你们中的大多数领袖都是非常明智的，他们能够避开问题，他们不会陷入到恐慌，
of them, I should say. And when you see, even
you people try to destroy Sahaja Yoga, they
你可以看到，即便你们有人想要破坏霎哈嘉瑜伽，
know you are doing it.
他们知道那些人在做些什么。
So to find out this eka karita, you have to
go deep down into yourself, by which you will
因此，为了达到这个eka karita，你必须要深入自己。
feel that you are all one. Whether you are
here or you are in Japan or in America, anywhere,
由此你能感受到你们都是一个整体，无论你在哪儿，是在日本、美国或是任何地方。
you all think the same way, you all help the
same cause, and you try to be the same style.
你们都以同样地方式思考，你们会帮助同样地事情，你们想要成为同一种类型。
I have seen people when they come for the
pujas, so many of them, how they enjoy each
我曾见到一些人，他们来参加普祭，许多人，
other’s company, how they try to help each
other.
他们是如何享受彼此的陪伴，如何努力去帮助彼此。
Somebody who is, say, in Russia or say, in
Bulgaria, anywhere, he will write to Me about
某个人，例如说在俄罗斯或者是在保加利亚，他会写信给我，
the problem he has, something. So somebody
from America, without I tell him, without
他有怎样的问题。在美国的某个人，无需我告诉他，
I inform him, without any information immediately
writes to Me, “Mother, such and such a person
无需我通知他，没有任何其他的信息，立刻他会写信给我：“母亲，
is there in Russia. Will You be able to send
that person to America?” Most of the time
有这样这样一个人在俄罗斯，你能否将这个人送到美国呢？”
it happens like this. But I don’t tell them.
I never ask them. Even if I ask, suddenly
许多时候，事情都是这样发生。但是我并没有告诉他们，我从未问过他们，即使我询问，
there will be a response from so many people
from so many countries, “Mother, this is
突然。在许多国家的众人之中会有一个回应：“母亲，
the problem? All right, we’ll go and do
it.”
是这个问题么?好吧，我们将会去解决它。”
For that I must say Austrians are very sensible
people in this respect, this eka karita. They
在一体性这一方面，我必须要说澳大利亚人是非常明智的。
went all the way to Jerusalem, you know, to
help the people, to get them realized. I wanted
他们去耶路撒冷，去帮助人们，给他们自觉。
to go to Jerusalem, but this bombing business
may not allow Me to go. But the Jerusalem
我想要去耶路撒冷，但是在这个开花结果的时代，可能并不允许我去。但是，耶路撒冷的人们，
people, I found them, found them to be much
more collective, because they came to Egypt.
他们非常的团结，具有集体性。因为他们去埃及。
I said, “Why have you come here?”
我问：“你们为什么要来这儿？”
“Made friends with the Muslims of Egypt.”
Just imagine! I was surprised. How could they
“与埃及的穆斯林成为朋友。”想象一下，我非常吃惊，
come here? No, just to make friends. “They
are Muslims, so we want to make friends with
他们怎么能够来这儿，只是为了交朋友。“他们是穆斯林，所以我们想要和他们成为朋友。”
them.” So making friendship without any
ulterior motive, without any gain, is one
没有任何外在的动机，没有想要获取任何，只是想要成为朋友，这是你们内在的一体性的显现。
of the signs of your eka karita. Not only
that you are satisfied with other Sahaja yogis,
不仅仅你和其他霎哈嘉瑜伽士是好朋友，
but you want to bring other Sahaja yogis in.
So many have done that. This is something
同样地，你还想要将其他霎哈嘉瑜伽士带进来。你们中许多人都这样做了。
so nourishing.
这是一件多么滋养的事情。
Now, as you are being enlightened, you get
another person who is enlightened. It’s
现在，因为你们已经获得自觉，你让另一个人也获得自觉。
very great joy-giving. If you give realization
to one person, you feel very happy. I mean,
这是非常令人感到喜悦的。如果你给予某人自觉，你会感到非常开心。
so many write to Me, “Mother, now we have
got thirty persons, twenty persons,” and
许多人写信给我：“母亲，现在我们已经有了三十人，二十人。”
they’re very happy about it, that we have
got so many Sahaja yogis. But doing that,
他们都非常为此感到高兴，我们有这么多霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
one should not develop the ego – then again
you go against Ganesha, because Christ, you
但是，你们不应该因此而发展自我--那会再次违背格涅沙原理，因为基督知道，
know, He doesn’t like it. Egoistical people
He doesn’t like, and He’s Shri Ganesh.
他不喜欢这个，他不喜欢自我的人。他就是锡吕格涅沙。
So He doesn’t like such people who out of
their ego want to create an organization of
所以，他不喜欢一些人只是为了满足自己的自我而创立一个自己的组织，
their own, and try to dominate others. This
kind of people they don’t like. Both of
由此尝试宰制他人，他们不喜欢这样的人。
them are the same, there is complete eka karita
between them. In the same way we too develop
基督和格涅沙是一样的，他们是有着完全的 eka karita，
that special quality of eka karita.
同样地，我们也要在内在发展这种一体的特质。
We forget about so-called religions that we
have. See now how they are fighting. All the
我们忘记了我们那所谓的宗教。看看现在宗教之间的斗争。
religions which are outside are fighting among
themselves. They are dishonest, they are doing
所有这些外在的宗教彼此之间都在争斗。他们不诚实
all kinds of wrong things – you know it
very well. It’s every day it’s in the
做尽所有的错事——对此你们都有所耳闻。
newspaper that you hear about what wrong they
are doing. They are little bit successful,
每天，在报纸上你们都能听到他们所做的错事。他们是有些成功
but not for a long time, because they will
be exposed. This is the time of exposure,
但持续不了多长时间了，因为他们将会得到揭露。揭露的时刻到了
that they will lose that great filth on which
they have been working out. All these will
他们将会失去他们做出的种种污秽
have to just disappear, these false ideas
about superiority of any religion. How can
那些关于一种宗教要优于其他宗教的错误观念，所有这些都会消失
a religion be superior to another one, which
is created by the effort of Shri Ganesha’s
一种宗教怎能高于另一种宗教？宗教都是基于Shri Ganesha的吉祥而被创造
auspiciousness? It’s not auspicious at all
that you fight another religion or you fight
与其他的宗教或与其他的教义去争斗一点也不吉祥
another creed, or you say that this is a lesser
race, or we are a higher race. All these false
或者你说这是次要的种族，或者我们是更高的种族
ideas, they drop out. This doesn’t remain
anymore, because all these ideas have created
所有这些错误的观念都会脱落。它将不再存在
problems.
因为所有这些观念都会带来问题
Say in America, they first hated the blacks,
so now the blacks are hating the whites. It’s
在美国，他们首先嫌恶黑人，于是现在黑人开始憎恨白人
a big turmoil going on, you see. Then we have,
also in India we had people who were supposed
于是骚动持续着。然后在印度，有一些人被认为是贱民
to be untouchables. They were tortured, they
were troubled, and they did a lot of wrong
他们被折磨，被找麻烦
things which they should have never done,
which is not written in the shastras. Because
他们做了许多他们本应从不会做的错事，这些在启愿诗（shastras）中未被记载
of that now they are acting against the so-called
“touchables” and putting them right in
正因为如此，所以现在他们开始反对所谓的“贵民”，以牙还牙
their own places. So this brings in conflict.
Shri Ganesha is the one, when He gives you
这些带来冲突。Shri Ganesha是那位给予你智慧的神祇
wisdom you understand that nobody is superior
to another person. You are all made by God,
由此你知道没有人比其他人更高。你们都是被神创造
and is whatever is made by God is auspicious
and beautiful. Once you start understanding
任何被神创造的都是吉祥和美丽的。一旦你们理解了这一点
that, this eka karita spreads outside also.
It spreads to other people. It’s not just
这个eka karita向外扩展，它扩展至其他人
because of a certain social understanding
and a social upliftment you try to be good
不单是某一个特定的社会理解它，或某一个社会得到提升
to others – no. It is from inside; inside
you do it.
你尝试对其他人友好——不是这样的。它是来自内在，从内在你做这些
This eka karita first must work in the family.
It’s very important. The family which is
Eka karita首先需要在家庭中成就出来，这是非常重要的
disturbed all the time cannot create children
who are in the state of eka karita. That’s
那些一直处于动乱的家庭不能创造出处于eka karita境界的孩子
why always tell them that don’t fight. In
the family they are fighting, they cannot
这就是为何一直告诉他们不能打架
be Sahaja yogis. If there is such a fight
it is better to get out of such a family.
如果在家庭中他们打架，他们就不能是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。如果有这样的争斗发生，那么最好离开这样的家庭
So we have sanctioned also a divorce. Any
man who is flirting with other women or doing
我们也允许离婚。任何一个与其他女人调情的男人，或做错误事情的人
wrong things, we have asked him to get out
of Sahaja Yoga. The reason is, one bad apple
我们会让他离开霎哈嘉瑜伽。原因在于
can spoil many apples. So such a man or such
a woman should be kept out of Sahaja Yoga
一个坏苹果会带坏许多苹果。因此这样的男人或女人将会被完全请出霎哈嘉瑜伽
completely so that there is a better family
relationship, which is very important in Sahaja
然后就会有更好的婚姻关系，在霎哈嘉瑜伽中
Yoga. Your family relationships should be
absolutely perfect. I can’t understand:
良好的婚姻关系是非常重要的。你的家庭关系应该绝对地完美
you can’t enjoy the company of your wife,
then what are you going to enjoy in this world?
我不能理解你不能享受你妻子的陪伴，若如此，在这世界上你还能享受谁？
If you cannot enjoy the bliss of your family
life, you cannot enjoy anything else.
如果你不能享受你的家庭生活这一福佑，你就不能享受任何事情
This very close relationship of husband/wife
is thrown apart because of Ganesha problem
只有当Shri Ganesha出问题时，这种亲密的夫妻关系才会出现问题
only. If the Ganesha was all right there would
have been a perfect union, perfect understanding
如果Shri Ganesha是妥善的，那么夫妻之间将会有完美的结合
between husband and wife. But that fails,
that means there’s definitely something
丈夫和妻子间将会有充分的谅解。但如果夫妻关系失败了
wrong with the Shri Ganesha. Try to correct
your own Shri Ganesh than to see to others.
则意味着Shri Ganesha一定出了一些问题。尝试纠正你自己的Shri Ganesha，而不是寻找他人的问题
You have to meditate, and meditate on Shri
Ganesh, to sit on the ground and meditate.
你必须要冥想，对Shri Ganesha冥想，坐在地上冥想
Now when we run away from the Mother Earth
and we don’t touch her, we don’t respect
当我们从大地母亲之处跑开时，我们不触摸她，不尊重她
her, in a way we don’t respect Shri Ganesha.
He was made out of the Mother Earth, and He
在某种程度上就是我们不尊重Shri Ganesha。祂是由大地之母处而来
controls the Mother Earth. He controls all
the five elements. Not only that, but He controls
祂掌控着大地之母。祂掌控着五大元素。
you.
不仅如此，祂还掌控着你
I liked the film yesterday where they showed
a Ganesha walking about with another person,
我喜欢昨天的电影，在电影里面演着Ganesha与另一个人漫步
who was telling “don’t do this, and don’t
do this.” It’s a very, very beautiful
祂一直在说“别做这个，别做这个”。这是一个非常非常美丽的电影
film, because it suggests that Ganesha is
always there to tell you not to do it. But
因为它揭示了Shri Ganesha一直在那儿告诉你该怎样做
if you do it then you develop all kinds of
horrible diseases, all kinds of horrible faces,
但如果你做了，那么你就会发展出各种各样可怕的疾病，各种恐怖的面孔
all kinds of family problems; also you can
develop national problems. So this is so important
各种家庭问题，你也会发展出国家之间的问题
to understand, that such a feeling of, I should
say, very inauspicious character are to be
因此，这种非常不吉祥的性格一定要避免，理解这点非常重要
avoided. I can’t understand, how can people
feel so bad about small, small children, some
我不能理解为何人们会对很小的小孩感觉糟糕
two-year-old child, some five-year-old child?
If you see a child, even a photograph of a
有些2岁大，有些5岁大。如果你看一个孩子，即使是一个孩子的照片
child, you feel like loving that, you feel
like kissing that child. If the children cannot
你就感到喜爱他，你感到想要亲吻那个孩子
be respected, how can you understand the value
of Shri Ganesha? See how sweet they are, how
如果儿童不受到尊重，你怎能理解Shri Ganesha的价值？看看他们是多么甜美啊
sweetly they behave, and they understand.
They understand you, they understand Me. I
他们的行为多么甜美，并且他们能够理解，他们理解你，他们也理解我
know, even the small children, those who are
very small, newly-born children understand
即使是非常小的孩子，刚出生的婴儿都理解我
Me. So there’s innately within them is built
in a kind of a feeling of understanding the
所以，在他们内在早已天赋了
love.
对爱的理解力
To understand the love also is very difficult
for egoistical people, because they love themselves,
对于自我导向的人来说，要理解爱是非常难的，因为他们只爱他们自己
they don’t love anybody else. Or if they
love somebody it is out of lust, maybe greed,
他们不爱任何人。或者即使他们爱某人，也是基于欲望，或者贪婪
maybe some sort of a association. But love
for love’s sake is only possible if your
或者某种联盟。但是只有当你的Shri Ganesha得到洁净和保持
Shri Ganesha is properly cleaned out and kept.
因爱而生的爱才有可能产生
We have come so far, and we have so many Sahaja
yogis all over the world. Of course I have
迄今为止，在全世界我们有如此多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
worked very hard, I must say, but you also
have supported Me very much. I am thankful
当然我为之非常努力地工作，但是你们也对我做了许多的支持
to you. It’s not possible in this Western
world specially, where there’s no consideration
我对你们表示感谢。尤其在这个不顾及Shri Ganesha原理的西方世界
of Ganesha’s Principle, that you people
should come out so well and accept Sahaja
你们这些人仍然进展的如此好
Yoga as a life for yourself.
并接受霎哈嘉瑜伽成为你们自己的生活
In Sahaja Yog the most important thing is
to worship Shri Ganesha within you, and the
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，最重要的事情就是崇拜你内在的Shri Ganesha
quality of Shri Ganesha within you. It’s
very soothing, it’s very peace-giving, it’s
崇拜你内在Shri Ganesha的素质。它非常的慰藉人心，给予许多的平安和安全感
very secure, security-creating power. If your
Ganesha is all right nobody can touch you,
是创造安全感的力量。如果你的Ganesha是妥当的，那么没有人可以触碰你
nobody can destroy you, nobody can upset you,
because He is the one who is the giver of
无人能摧毁你，无人能惹恼你。
peace.
因为祂是那位给予平安的人
The world peace is disturbed because we have
not worshipped Shri Ganesha. I have seen people
因为我们不崇拜Shri Ganesha，世界和平受到打扰
in very big positions, in charge of military,
in charge of that, in charge – not in charge
我见过许多位居高位的人，他们掌管着军队，掌管着这那——但却无法掌管他们自己
of themselves. Their Ganesha is absolutely
ruined and finished. All such people are such
他们的Ganesha完全崩溃和完结。这些人是国家的领导人
leaders of nations, and people try to follow
them in their own way. Though they may do
人们还尝试以自己的方式跟随他们
something secretly, doesn’t matter; people
know about it. Because in auspiciousness if
尽管他们秘密地做一些事情，没关系，人们会知道它
you are losing, then the whole world comes
to know, somehow. It will all be exposed,
因为在吉祥中，如果你有所闪失，那么整个世界都会以某种方式知道它，它会得到揭露
because Satya Yuga has come. In this new Yuga
there’s light of the truth within us, and
因为黄金时代已经来临。在这新的时代，真理之光在我们之内
this truth can expose all that is nonsensical
we have been doing.
这个真理会揭露我们做过的所有荒谬的事
Now truth is the quality of Shri Ganesh Himself.
He’s the one who is giving us truth. In
真理就是Shri Ganesha祂自身的素质。祂就是那位给予我们真理的神祇
our brain it comes to us through Jesus Christ.
Jesus Christ has worked so much, He’s done
祂通过耶稣基督来到我们的头脑中。耶稣为之付出了极大的努力
so much; but look at the condition of the
people who are supposed to be following Him,
祂做了如此之多。然而，看看那些跟随祂的人们的情况吧
look at the way they are behaving. Let us
at least show that if you follow Ganesha and
看看他们行径如何。如果你跟随Ganesha和耶稣基督
Jesus Christ, you are in the image of that
personality which is something so very spiritual.
那么至少你要有非常属灵的性格
Spiritual life is the giver of joy. You cannot
灵性生活是喜悦的赐予者  除了灵性
get joy out of anything else but spirituality.
你不能从其他任何事物中获得喜悦
You can get some satisfaction, you can get
你可以得到一些满足感  你可以得到
some ego, you might feel that you are something
一些自我  你可能感觉你很伟大
great, but the only way you can get the inner
但是你获得内在平安喜乐的唯一方法
peace and joy is Shri Ganesha’s manifestation
是锡吕格涅沙在所有的轮穴之中的显现
in all the chakras. He manifests in all the
祂在所有的轮穴中显现
chakras which, when you are in a proper state
当你在这些轮穴上表现恰当的状态
on those chakras, you get the joy, and that
你获得喜乐
joy comes to you through Shri Ganesh.
并且这份喜乐通过锡吕格涅沙带给你
These days people are writing horrible books,
这些日子人们正在写恐怖的书籍
horrible things. Also there are some who are
做恐怖的事情  并且有一些人
trying to write very sweet things about Shri
正在尝试写很甜蜜的事
Ganesha’s principle of understanding, principle
关于对锡吕格涅沙原理的理解和祂的吉祥原理
of His auspiciousness. Very sweetly I have
非常甜蜜  我已经知道一些人已经写下
seen some people have written some very, very
一些关于祂的极之甜蜜的故事
sweet stories about Him. It’s not only the
不仅是爱情故事
love stories – up to a point, all right,
在一定程度上  好吧
they created so many love stories, love stories,
他们创造了如此多的爱情故事  爱情故事
love stories. Now something beyond that one
爱情故事  现在我们知道在这之上
has to know. And beyond that is this Ganesha
在这之上是锡吕格涅沙原理
Principle, which is of complete peace, of
是完全的平安的原理
complete joy, and of understanding of love,
完全的喜乐原理  和对爱和纯洁之爱的价值的理解的原理
the value of pure love; of giving, and also
是给予的原理  也是获取的原理
of taking it. Anyone who gives you the pure
任何给你纯洁之爱的人
love should be understood in the right way.
应该以正确的方式被理解
I yesterday knew that Shri Ganesha has gone
我昨天知道锡吕格涅沙已经走远了一些
off a little bit. I don’t know why He was
我不知道祂为什么这样
like that, but one has to understand that
但是我们必须明白
there must be some people within us who do
在我们之中一定有人
not follow the Principle of Shri Ganesh, and
没有遵循锡吕格涅沙原理
that’s why these troubles are there. So
并且这就是为什么有这些问题
with sincere heart and a sincere mind if you
所以如果你带着真诚的心
ask the blessings of Shri Ganesh, He’s always
向锡吕格涅沙寻求祝福
ready to give you. But if you don’t listen
祂总是准备好给与你祝福  但是如果你不听从祂
to Him and if you destroy your chastity in
并且如果你以任何方式摧毁你的贞洁
any way, He will punish you. He’ll not spare
祂将惩罚你   祂将不会宽恕你
you, He doesn’t have the idea of sparing.
祂没有宽恕的概念
At the level of Christ only, He thought of
仅仅在基督的层次上  祂考虑宽恕
forgiving, of forgiving you. But forgiving
考虑宽恕你
doesn’t mean that any sin can be forgiven
但是宽恕并不意味着所有的罪都能被宽恕
– no. This is a kind of controlling power.
并不是这样  这是一种控制权
Christ has said that you’ll be forgiven,
基督曾说你将被宽恕
but Shri Ganesha at a point, when He sees
但是在某一点上锡吕格涅沙  当祂看见人们正在原谅
people are forgiving, He tries to punish you.
祂试图惩罚你
That’s the limiting point where He thinks
这是限制性的一点
it’s not proper to forgive such and such
在这点上祂认为不适合去原谅这样  那样的人
person. So for Christ, to forgive is all right
所以对于基督来说  宽恕没什么问题
but for Ganesha, He has to expose and punish
但是对锡吕格涅沙
the person.
祂不得不揭露和惩罚那个人
So in a way you have to know that Christ is
所以有一点我们必须知道耶稣是非常伟大
very great, because He gives us the forgiving
因为他给予我们宽恕的力量
power, and Shri Ganesha is very powerful because
并且锡吕格涅沙是十分有力量的
He limits our forgiving. You may forgive anyone.
因为祂限制我们的宽恕  你可能宽恕任何人
You may say that “I would like to forgive,”
你可能说“我愿意去宽恕”
but we don’t know if Shri Ganesh will allow
但是我们不知道锡吕格涅沙是否会允许它达到这个程度
it to that extent. And Christ accepts that,
并且基督接受这个
because they are the same, they are like the
因为他们是一样的
two sides of one coin. So we cannot depend
他们就像一枚银币的两面
too much on the forgiveness power of Christ,
所以我们不可以过度依赖基督宽恕的力量
because there is Ganesha always sitting there
因为格涅沙总是安坐在那
and He has in His hand, you have seen, a very
并且你们可以看到在祂手上
powerful weapon.
有十分有力量的武器
He is the one who is just peace, who is coolness,
他只是和平的那个  是平静的那个
who gives you coolness after realization.
他给与我们自觉之后的平静
You get the cool breeze because of Shri Ganesh,
你因为从锡吕格涅沙处得到凉风
because – it is Brahmachaitanya, no doubt,
因为– 这是Brahmachaitanya  毫无疑问
but the one who emits it is Shri Ganesha.
但是发出它的人是锡吕格涅沙
He cools you down. He brings you down to a
祂你凉下来  祂使你成为
very cool, satisfied, and a person with complete
一个非常清凉  满足  完全的平静的人
calmness. With that calmness you become all
借由这种平静你们所有人成为一体
one. This eka karita is established, oneness
eka karita被建立 同一性被建立
is established. Whatever country you may be
无论你生活在哪个国家
living in, whatever country you may be proud
无论你为哪个国家骄傲
of, you will see the bad things in that country
你将看见这个国家的缺点
and you will try to improve that. You’ll
并且你将尝试去改善
not be identified with the bad. This is the
你将不因这些缺点被识别
greatest thing of the Satya Yuga, that it
这是Satya Yuga最伟大的事
exposes, and you do not support something
它揭露并且你不支持错误的事
that is wrong, which is being done as a aggression
和做富有侵略性的事
– you don’t accept. And once you don’t
你不接受  并且一旦你不接受它
accept that, then you start becoming one with
你开始与人们成为整体
the people who are one with you. And they
人们与你成为一个整体
all believe in the same thing, their ideas
并且他们都相信同样的事
are the same, their thinking is the same,
他们的想法是相同的  他们的思考是相同的
their joy is the same, and they enjoy each
他们的喜乐是相同的  并且他们非常享受彼此
other very much. They become one, and this
他们成为一体  并且这个同一性
oneness has to be established fully in Sahaja
必须在霎哈嘉瑜伽中建立
Yoga. Some people who are only interested
一些人只是岁赚取金钱感兴趣
in making money, who are interested in getting
一些人对低层次的聚会
a good crowd or some sort of a thing of a
或者低层次的各类事情感兴趣
very low level, cannot; those who are in Sahaja
不能这样  那些在霎哈嘉中
Yoga to find wives for themselves or husbands
为他们自己寻找妻子或丈夫的人
for themselves, aren’t.
不能这么做
This spirituality grows with humility. And
灵性在谦卑中成长
the humility of Ganesha is told by His venture
并且格涅沙的谦卑在  祂的冒险  中被告知
once, when His Mother asked Him that “The
曾经  当祂的妈妈问他
one who will go round the Earth three times,
谁将绕大地三次
I’ll give Him a present.”
我将给他一个礼物
So Ganesha thought, “Who is greater than
所以格涅沙想  谁会比我妈妈更伟大
My Mother? Not this Earth.” He had a small
不是这大地
little rat on which He used to travel. This
祂乘坐一只小老鼠
shows that He was so humble: on a rat He could
这表现出祂是如此谦卑
travel, no pressure on the rat. And while
祂能够用一只老鼠做坐骑  没有给那只老鼠压力
His brother Kartikeya had a peacock which
与此同时祂的兄弟锡吕卡提凯亚有只可以飞的孔雀
could fly, so He knew He cannot go round the
祂知道祂不能在祂兄弟之前环绕世界
world before His brother. So He just went
在祂兄弟之前环绕世界  所以他只是围着他的母亲转了三圈
round His Mother three times, and He got the
围着他的母亲转了三圈
present.
他得到了礼物
This shows one thing, that speed is not the
这表明一件事  速度并不是成功的方式
way of success. You have to slow down your
你必须放慢你的速度
speed. Apart from that, you have to understand
除了这点  你必须去理解
what is the most important thing, as He understood
什么是最重要的事  就像格涅沙理解的
the most important thing is to love your Mother,
最重要的事是去爱你的母亲
to respect your Mother, and know that She’s
去尊重你的母亲
the highest, She’s the greatest. And that
并且知道祂是至高的  祂是最伟大的
is how He has been expressed within ourselves.
只是祂已经在我们之内表达方式
Once that happens, your spirituality grows.
一旦发生  你的灵性得到成长
I hope you will work it out this way now,
我希望现在你们现在用这种方式成就锡吕格涅沙
Shri Ganesha, and start an eka karita. I don’t
并且开始an eka karit
like people writing letters against their
我不喜欢人们写信反对他们的领袖
leaders, against this man, against that man.
反对这个人  反对那个人
That’s not good. There’s no need. If you
这不好  这是没有必要的
just can be forgiving, and keeping one with
如果你只是宽恕  并且与彼此成为一体
each other. Try to get more people, and more
尝试去团结更多的人  更多的人
people. You cannot separate anyone as saying
你不能区分他人
that they are condemned, and they are no good.
说他们被定罪  并且说他们不好
Try to get them. With your forgiveness, with
尝试去团结他们  用你的宽恕
your sense of chastity, things will improve.
用你的贞洁感  事情将会得到改善
So this exclusiveness also should be given
所以这排他性也应该被抛弃
up, which perhaps comes from a kind of a sense
我认为这种排他性可能来自于一种不安全感
of insecurity, I think. It is Shri Ganesha.
是锡吕格涅沙
If they are wrong type of people, He drives
如果他们是错误类型的人
them out. So don’t get frightened of them,
他会让他们离开  因此不要对他们产生恐惧
and don’t get upset with them. Try to be
和不要对他们感到困扰  尝试
one, one, and try to be more attracting people
去成为一个整体  一个整体  并且尝试成为更有吸引力的人
to yourself, keeping them to you, trying to
和他们在一起
manage them and look after them.
尝试去管理他们并且照顾他们
I hope you will all meditate now after this
我希望你们所有人将在这之后冥想
to develop your Ganesha qualities, and develop
去发展你的锡吕格涅沙的特质
that power of chastity, and also of peace
去发展贞洁的力量
and security.
平安的力量
May God bless you.
愿神祝福你